我上周在这里
I was here last week.
你他妈死哪儿去了
Where the fuck were you?
我的肝终于要不行了
My liver is finally giving up.
-那我们该怎么办  -没办法
- What do we do? - Nothing we can do,
除非有人愿意捐肝给我
unless somebody wants to give me their liver.
斯坦把酒吧留给我了
Stan gave me the bar.
你怎么会想要它
Why would you want it?
没看最近的账目吗
Have you looked at the books lately?
你们家里的人可以为他捐一部分肝脏
Someone from your family can donate a portion of their liver.
你可以看看他们与你的父亲血型是否相符
Why don't you find out if their blood matches your father?
我想让你验下这个
I need you to test this.
你们看
Take a look.
双胞胎
Two babies?
不对  有三个呢
Nope. Mm, three.
三胞胎
Triplets!
我的老二可牛逼了  兄弟
I got a magic penis, man.
好了  哪些同学提前读完了第七章
Okay, who has read ahead to chapter seven?
我才十三
I'm only 13.
好吧
Uh, okay.
没事
Cool.
他快死了
He's dying.
他酗酒成性  把自己的肝喝坏了
He drank through the liver that he had, and he wrecked it.
现在要来把我的也喝坏吗
And now he wants to wreck mine.
-不  绝不可能  -没关系  儿子
- No. No way. - It's okay, son.
既然菲奥娜不肯  我只好去找另一个女儿了
If Fiona won't do it, I'll get my other daughter to.
黛比太小了
Debbie's too young.
我的大女儿  萨曼莎
My oldest daughter, Samantha.
什么
What?
无耻家庭
第四季第三集
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：  扎克不渣    重案组李Sir    姚小事    君君
■
翻译：  青椒    爱卿遛小鸟    拉图    Greentie
时间轴：  大喷子    没有影子    旺TY的Jessie
■
校对： Greentie      落
后期： 孤帆          总监： 落
■
这是我最后一次
That is the last time
让来你选清晨放的歌了
I let you choose the tunes in the morning.
是吗  你就继续装你讨厌
Oh, yeah, you just keep acting
英国男孩团体吧
like you hate British boy bands.
-我觉得这歌很好听  -没人喜欢他们
- I think it's adorable. - Everybody hates them.
真抱歉我不是12岁的小姑娘了
I'm sorry I'm not a 12-year-old girl.
是啊  我一般也不跟小于14岁的上床
Yeah, well, I usually don't go lower than 14.
下次我们可以听你喜欢的黑帮说唱
And, you know, next time we can listen to your gangsta rap.
坎耶的歌什么时候成黑帮说唱了
Since when is Kanye considered gangsta rap?
一直都是吧  你是从哪里了解音乐的
Uh, since always. Where'd you learn about music?
-你是火星人吗  -从你妈那里
- You living on Mars? - Your mom...
-是吗  -上次我跟她干了一炮
- Oh, yeah? - Last time I banged her.
是吗  这就难怪了
Oh, yeah, that makes a lot more sense.
她的品位很糟糕
She has awful taste.
那个  你要是愿意的话
Hey, you know, you can leave
可以把东西放在我这
some of that stuff here if you want.
-放什么东西  -像是化妆品  内衣  洗发水
- What stuff? - Makeup, underwear, shampoo.
看来你是认真的
Oh, wow. This is serious.
一两套正装什么的
Work outfit or two-- just stuff.
我会考虑看看的
Uh-huh. I'll think about it.
或者我住你那边也行
Or I could just stay at your place.
-这事我们谈过了  不行  -我们没谈过
- We talked about this. No way. - We have not.
没有  我们还没谈过这事
No, we have not talked about this.
你总说"情况很复杂"
You always just say, "It's complicated."
-确实很复杂  -你倒是说说看呀
- It's very complicated. - Well, try me.
好吧  我爸  他现在又跟我们住一起了
Okay. My father, who now lives with us again,
之前酗酒到肝衰竭
drank himself into liver failure
现在正游说子女们捐肝给他
and is trolling his children for a new liver,
包括一个之前从未跟我们提起的大女儿
including an older daughter that none of us knew about.
你还有个姐姐
You have another sister?
指不定有20个呢
I probably have 20.
每当我以为自己对弗兰克知根知底了的时候
Just when I think I've peeled the onion on Frank,
-嘭  他就又扔个猛料过来  -好吧
- bam, another layer. - Right.
好处就是  我现在对撒手不管擅长得很
The upside is I'm getting real good at not giving a shit.
我听着觉得你还是没法不管呢
Well, it sounds to me like maybe you do give a shit.
那你要去查下听力了  能借你的牙刷一用吗
Get your hearing tested. Can I use your toothbrush?
-真恶心  可以  -谢了
- Gross. Yes. - Thank you.
别忘了今晚在我爸妈家吃晚饭的事
Oh, hey, don't forget-- dinner at my parents' place tonight.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
真是抱歉  亲爱的
I'm so sorry, sweetie.
真是抱歉  稍等
I'm so sorry. Hold on.
你好  菲奥娜
Hi, Fiona.
是利亚姆在哭吗
Is that Liam screaming?
那个  是的
Well, yes.
是他  我刚才给他剪指甲来着
Yes, I was just clipping his nails,
不小心剪到他一点点了
and I just nicked him a little bit.
-怪我好久没给小孩剪指甲了  -那他没事吧
- I'm out of practice. - Is he okay?
没事  他挺好的  没什么大碍
Yes, he's fine. He's totally fine.
那黛比和卡尔怎么样
How's Debbie and Carl?
我感觉好久没见过他们了
I feel like I haven't seen them in forever.
卡尔刚去上学了
Carl just left for school,
黛比也快走了
and Debbie's getting ready.
她一直在教我怎么用我的iPad
And she's been teaching me how to use my new ipad.
我找到了一个关于宗谱的应用
I found this genealogy app,
原来我还有1/32的梅诺米尼人[北美印第安人]血统呢
and it turns out I'm 1/32 Menominee Indian.
-谁会料到呢  -那个
- Huh. Who knew? - Anyway...
你知道"基督混一混"这个网站吗
do you know about christianmingle.com?
-那是相亲网站吗  -是的
- Is that a dating site? - Well, yes, it is.
原来  基督徒的交友网站有11个之多呢
And it turns out, there's 11 Christian dating sites,
而且我家附近就有不少符合条件的单身汉
and there's a lot of eligible bachelors in my neighborhood.
他们看起来都还算正常
And they all seem mostly normal.
我下班后立马回家
Well, I will be home right after work.
再次感谢你照看孩子们过夜
Thanks again for watching the kids overnight.
我真不愿意丢下他们
I hate leaving them.
没事  我很乐意照顾他们
It's no problem. It's been so fun.
祝你今天愉快
Have a good day, okay?
亲爱的  外面可冷了
Hey, sweetie, it's freezing outside.
我会呆在室内  早餐呢
I'll be indoors. Breakfast?
那个  鸡蛋  牛奶  面包都没有了
Well, there wasn't any eggs or milk or bread.
-我饿死了  -真抱歉
- I'm starving. - I'm sorry.
要不你在上学的路上买点东西吃吧
Can you pick up something on the way to school,
比如麦满分什么的
like an Egg Mcmuffin or something?
我给了卡尔一些钱
I gave Carl some money
让他放学后买些食物回来
so he could buy some groceries after school.
这是什么
What was that?
有人"戳"我了 有人"戳"我了
I got poked. I got poked.
昨天我"戳"的那个美洲印第安人
I got poked back by the American Indian guy
回应我了  我该怎么办
that I poked yesterday. What do we do?
"我们有很多相似之处
"We have a lot in common.
我是纯正的基卡普人
I am full-blooded Kickapoo Indian.
我爱笑声  美食  名胜古迹  还有上帝
I love laughter, food, scenic views, and the lord.
咱们聊聊吧"
Let's talk."
然后怎么办
Now what?
问他是不是想"DTF"
Uh, ask him if he's D.T.F.
"DTF"  那是什么意思
D.T.F. What does that even mean?
好吧  我就问他是不是想"DTF"
Okay, I got to ask him if he's D.T.F.
老天呐
Oh, god.
你还好吧  老爸
You okay, dad?
还好  还好
Uh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
我身体倍儿棒
I'm fit as a fiddle,
只是止痛药昨晚吃完了
except I-I ran out of perckie "CS" last night.
我能帮上什么忙吗
Is there anything I could do?
再多弄点呗
Get more.
那是她吗
Is that her?
原来我闺女长这样啊
So that's my daughter.
还挺漂亮的
She's kind of beautiful.
完全就是乞丐版的你
Looks like you in skank form.
多谢夸奖  儿子
Thank you, son.
我岂不是当舅舅了
Does that make me an uncle?
可不
Yes, indeed.
接下来怎么办
Now what?
这个嘛
Well...
让我给她展示一下加拉格基因的魔力
I give her a taste of the old Gallagher magic.
你  你身上带了现金吗
You--you got any cash?
希拉给了我40块买吃的
Sheila gave me $40 for groceries.
交给我  我要买大麻
Hand it over. I need weed.
儿子  我都走不动路了
Son, I can hardly walk.
我认为让我行动起来更重要
I think ambulation takes precedence.
那我们吃什么
What will we eat now?
你是个聪明的孩子
You're a bright kid.
相信你会有别的办法
I'm sure you'll figure out something.
好吧
Look...
给你
Here...
够买面包和厕纸了
There's enough for bread and T.P.
赶紧去
Shoo.
弄点药片回来
Get hard drugs.
让你老爹骄傲一下
Make daddy proud.
-你竟然迟到了  -我设了早上六点的闹钟
- You can't be serious. - I set my alarm for 6:00 A.M.
想逃避道德谴责的胆小鬼才会找借口
Excuse is the refuge of the moral coward.
老兄  我昨天就睡了三小时
Dude, I got three hours of sleep.
熬夜学经济学来着
I was up all night studying for Econ.
其他上早班的混蛋也是
So did every other jerk on morning shift.
这叫"半工半读"  不是"半读半工"
It's called work-study, not study-work.
我已经很努力了  混蛋  好吗
I'm trying, asshole, all right?
-放我一马  -那就再努力一点
- Cut me some slack. - Try harder.
核桃和葡萄干的盘子空了
Walnut and raisin dishes are empty.
保温台上全是糖浆
Steam table is covered in syrup.
擦干净  换一批新的
Clean that up, make a new batch,
还有别跟我摆脸色  伙计
and lose the 'tude, dude.
这个像小凯
This one looks like Kev.
这个像我
This one looks like me.
这个要么像我表弟特罗伊
And this one either looks like my cousin Troy
马文·盖伊  20世纪中期美国著名歌手  有"摩城王子"之称
要么就像马文·盖伊
or Marvin Gaye.
我只是来拿止痛药的
Yeah, I just came here for the painkillers.
你要是以为我会让你免费拿走
If you think I'm gonna load you up on my hard-won,
我辛苦弄来的高档药片
top-shelf pharmaceuticals pro bono,
那你就是脑残了
you are one fry short of a happy meal.
药不能免费给你 谁都不行
No freebies, not for you, not for anyone.
你要收我买药的钱吗
You're charging me for drugs now?
宝贝  现在我们进入了求生模式
Honey, we are in survival mode.
你不是要做贫民窟的护士吗
What happened to ghetto nurse?
她成为资本主义者了
She became a capitalist.
我可以在中学帮你卖欧治
I could sell for you big market for oxy in middle school.
不行  赶紧走
No. Vamoose.
我得准备一下去酒吧了
I got to get ready and go to the bar.
走吧
Go.
拜
Bye.
别碰
你脸色差到极点了
You're in bad shape.
说点我不知道的行吗
Well, tell me something I don't know.
能看一下你的证件吗
Could I see your card?
可以
Yes.
是合法的
It's legit too,
跟这帮鼻涕虫不一样
not like these whiners.
你有什么具体的要求吗
Are you looking for anything specific?
有
Uh, yeah.
要一些能不让我觉得
Something to make me not feel
像被一支挥舞着大刀的新纳粹军队
like I'm being stabbed repeatedly
一刀一刀捅的感觉
by a small army of knife-wielding Neo-Nazis.
有缓解慢性关节炎的"艾琳大麻"
Well, we have Irene Kush for chronic arthritis,
缓解焦虑和慌张的"馊牛仔"
Sour Diesel for anxiety and panic attacks,
缓解肌肉痉挛的"大佛乳酪"
Big Buddha Cheese for muscle spasms.
有缓解严重肝受损的吗
What about for fatal liver damage?
我们不建议肝硬化的人吸大麻
Oh, we don't recommend bud for cirrhosis.
研究表明  很可能由中度
Studies show a significantly higher rate
恶化成重度纤维症
of moderate to severe fibrosis,
-或是组织受损  在普遍...  -好了  没事
- or tissue scarring, in regular-- - Okay, fine.
不用跟我讲药监局的警告
Let's skip the fda warning.
给我来一盎司"大佛"
Give me an ounce of the Buddha
一张食用品目录  还有试用品  免费的试用品
and a medibles menu and some samples, free samples.
这些钱够买
Um, this will get you, like,
八分之一盎司劣质的大麻  还有两块饼干
an eighth of low-grade schwag and two cookies.
成交
Sold.
他有个小习惯  在思考的时候
And he does this, like, little wheeze thing
会发出一点喘息声  就好像是这样
when he's thinking, kind of like a little, "hmm."
他不喜欢体育  我也不喜欢体育
And he doesn't like sports, and I don't like sports.
他以前在学校乐队里吹小号
And he used to play the trumpet in marching band,
但是按键坏了之后他就退出了
but he dropped out when his valve button broke.
他还有超多的复古T恤
And he has this enormous collection of vintage t-shirts.
我觉得...  我不知道
I feel like--I don't know. I don't know.
觉得你爱他吗
Like you love him?
觉得我非常喜欢他  我不知道
Like I really like him. I don't know.
我感觉  每次想到他心都疼一下
I feel like my heart hurts when I think of him.
那你俩打算什么时候做
So when do you plan on doing it?
快了吧
Um, soon?
-你们在等什么  -他还没有提出来
- What are you even waiting for? - He hasn't asked yet.
你要是喜欢他  就直接做呗
If you're in like with him, then why not just do it?
好的
Okay.
如果疼的话  不要尖叫
And if it hurts, don't squeal--
男生会失去性趣
huge turn-off for guys.
完事儿之后  一定记得尿尿
And make sure you pee right afterwards,
你就不会得性病了
so you don't get an STD.
完事后相互依偎时
And when you cuddle afterwards,
让他从后面抱着你
let him be the big spoon.
-我要怎么开始  -在他出其不意的时候
- How do I start? - When he's not expecting it...
突然  你就脱掉裤子
Bam, you drop trou
然后就搔首弄姿
and expos-ay some sex-ay.
是的  男生最爱那些
Yeah, boys go cray over that stuff.
我没有性感内裤
I don't own any sexy undies.
闺蜜  你看过我的内衣抽屉吗
Homegirl, have you seen my underwear drawer?
芝加哥家庭援助
收到我发给你的链接了吗
Get that link I just sent?
这是什么
What is this?
是个本地的戒酒协会
It's the, uh, local al-anon chapter.
我要用它来干嘛
Uh-huh. And what am I supposed to do with it?
没什么  但你可以通过它找到当地的互助组
Nothing, but you could use it to find a local meeting,
如果你想的话
if you wanted to.
它帮我们渡过了很多难关
It got us through some pretty rough moments.
-"我们"  - 是的  我全家
- "Us"? - Yeah, my whole family.
你们全家一起去互助组吗
Your whole family went to meetings?
我们全家一起去了  是的
My whole family went to meetings. Sure.
和处在相同困境的人们谈谈心
I mean, it helps to talk to people
对自己有帮助
in similar situations, you know?
所以谈心就能解决所有问题了吗
Oh. So talking solved all your problems?
我没那么说
Didn't say that.
你用你的方式解决你家的问题
You deal with your family shit your way,
我用我的方式解决我家的
and I will deal with mine my way,
即是  置之不理
which is not dealing with it at all.
好吧  那要是很管用的话
Okay. Well, if that works so well,
我为什么不能住你家
then why can't I stay at your place?
算你厉害
Well played.
别让我当啰嗦鬼
Don't make me out to be a nag.
我不是在告诉你该怎么做
I'm not telling you what to do.
我只是告诉你我们是怎么做的  好吗
I'm just telling you what we did, all right?
接不接受随便
So take it or leave it.
明天我会丢几个
I'll drop a couple of duffle bags
装满衣物和洗漱用品的大包在你家  行了吧
full of clothing and toiletries at your place tomorrow, okay?
太好了
Yes.
-只有这些吗  -不止
- This all you got? - Nope.
如果你表现得好
Got a tight roll of quarters behind my fly
我的裤子拉链后面还藏着大麻烟卷
with your name on it, if you play your cards right.
是你的小孩
That your kid?
是  随意播种  无所畏惧
Yep, I'm not afraid to knock a bitch up.
你要来吗
You game?
求你别再说话了
Please stop talking.
日用品搞定了
Groceries have been gotten.
现在该弄买药钱了
Now all I need is drug money.
有什么想法吗
Any ideas?
可以把你卖了
Could sell you.
汪星人
Doggy.
悠着点  发网小弟
Whoa. Slow your roll, hairnet.
想吃点午餐吗  有馅饼
You want some lunch, dude? Hot pockets?
-我们只有两个  -不要了  我没事
- We only have two. - No, you know what? I'm good.
我哲学课要迟到了
I'm gonna be late for philosophy.
-有打算洗澡吗  -怎么  我发臭了吗
- You gonna shower? - What? Do I need one?
-臭死了  -不了  没时间
- Yes. - Uh, no. No time.
我会喷点除臭剂
I'm just gonna have to spray some Axe
希望大家别呆在我的下风向了
and hope everybody stays upwind.
今天晚上能借你电脑一用吗
Um, hey, could I use your laptop tonight?
图书馆的电脑被
The computer at the library got hijacked
24小时的星际争霸锦标赛霸占了
by a 24-hour Starcraft tournament.
我真的必须写哲学课的论文了
You know, I really need to work on my paper for philosophy.
没问题  不过你为什么不
Sure, but why don't you just get
买台超便宜的宏碁网络本呢
one of those cheap-ass little Acer Chromebooks?
-那是什么玩意  -低端电脑  实在货
- What the hell's chromebook? - Low-end computer, no frills.
是吗  多少钱
Oh, yeah. How much?
翻新机才两百块
Refurbs are only about two hundy.
好吧  等我先买一台奔驰GT
Right. Sure, right after I buy that Mercedes G.T.
我会关注的
I've had my eye on.
好
Good.
薰衣草味的  真清新
Oh. Lavender-- it's refreshing.
-好了  我走了  -拜
- All right, see you. - Bye.
失狗招领
在我们深入
Before we delve too deeply into...
研究福柯
into Foucault
和现代性的问题之前  我要提醒你们
and problems of modernity, let me remind you
明天是你们纸质版论文的截稿日期
that hard copies of your papers are due tomorrow
上午九点之前交到我的邮箱
in my mailbox at 9:00 A.M.,
晚一分钟也不行
not 9:20, not 9:07.
好了
Good.
米歇尔·福柯是法国的历史学家  哲学家
Michel Foucault was a French historian and philosopher,
与结构主义
associated with the structuralist
和后结构主义运动有密切关系
and post-structuralist movements.
他对大范围的人道主义
He's had quite a strong influence
和社会科学
on a wide range of humanistic
-有重要影响  -抱歉  打一扰下
- and social scientific... - Sorry, one second.
不好意思
Sorry.
谢了
Thank you.
注意课堂纪律
Disciplines.
他在1950至1953年间
He joined the French Communist Party from
加入了法国共产党
1950 to 1953.
你看到长椅上那个胖墩了吗
You see Mr. Pudgy over there on the bench?
看到了
Yeah.
给你根大麻烟卷  帮我教训教训他
I'll give you a joint to smack him around a little bit.
拿着 政府认可的A级大麻
Here, grade "A" Government-approved weed.
等我暗号
Wait for my nod.
下手也别太狠了
And don't--don't get too rough on him.
那是我外孙
That's my grandson.
-离那孩子远点  -这他妈怎么回事
- Get away from that kid. - What the fuck?
你有病吗
What's the matter with you?
快走  快走
Go, go.
没事了  孩子  站起来
There you go, kid. Get up.
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
宝贝  你没事吧
Baby, are you okay?
他打我  我干什么了
He hit me. What did I do?
过来  坐这儿
Come on. Sit down right here.
老天  太感谢你了
God. Thank you so much.
有的孩子就是混蛋  对吧
I guess some kids are just assholes, huh?
你的小孩也在这里上学吗
Do you have a child who goes here?
不不  我只是路过
No, no, no. I was just walking by.
我在旁边的退役军人医院做志愿者
I volunteer at the VA hospital down the street,
帮助那些受伤的士兵
helping out wounded warriors.
有些人会揍不停  你可能会受伤
Not everyone would've stopped. You could've been hurt.
是啊  我猜我无法容忍不公之事
Yeah, well, I guess I'm just allergic to injustice.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
还好  我今天没吃午饭
Yeah. I skipped lunch today.
有点头晕
I'm just a bit dizzy.
我们正要去吃炸鱼薯条
We were just gonna head out for some fish and chips.
-你要一起吗  -不了
- Would you join us? - Oh, no.
我不能
No, I-I couldn't.
去吧  让我给你买点芝士条
Please, let me buy you some cheese fries.
我应该的
It's the least I can do.
好吧
Well--
嘿  亲爱的家人们
Hey, family.
昨晚有想我吗
Did you miss me last night?
我可想你们了
'Cause I missed you.
是你的男朋友吗
Is that your boyfriend?
是
Yeah.
他叫什么名字
What's his name?
你的男朋友  他叫什么
Your boyfriend-- what's his name?
马蒂
Matty.
你班里的吗
Someone in your class?
我记得我第一个男朋友
I remember my first boyfriend,
路易·沃巴
Louie Velba.
我抓到他和凯丽·施特劳斯
I caught him jamming his tongue down
在化学课上接吻
Kerri Strauss' throat in chemistry,
我就用煤气灯点着了她的头发
So I lit her hair on fire with a bunsen burner.
你们好呀
Hi, guys.
-还生气呢  -还藏着你的肝呢
- Still pissed? - Still hoarding your liver?
对  在学校过得怎么样
Yes. How was school today?
有没有解剖什么小死物
Did you perform surgery on anything small or dead?
汪星人真可爱  哪来的
Sweet doggy. Where'd you get him?
我会一直烦你的  小子
Well, I'm gonna keep trying, kiddo,
你最好习惯一下
so you might as well get used to it.
希拉在哪里
Where's Sheila?
你吓到我了  对不起
You frightened me. I'm sorry.
我以为你今天晚上会出去吃饭
I thought you were going out to dinner tonight.
我是要去  你在干嘛
I am. What are you doing?
我只是想找条围巾
Well, I was just looking for a scarf
或者毛衣  随便什么撩人的都行
or-or a sweater or something provocative
因为罗杰·奔跑·树想看我的全身照
because Roger Running Tree wants a full-body shot.
真对不起  我应该先问你的
I'm so sorry. I should've asked first.
没事  没关系  随便拿吧
No, no. It's--it's okay. Go on, take whatever you want.
很抱歉  我又得撤了
I'm sorry to duck out again.
只是我几周之前就答应了麦克
It's just--I promised Mike weeks ago that I'd--
真的
Seriously.
真的  没事的
Seriously, it is so fine.
我们在一起很开心
We're having a wonderful time.
是啊  我是想尽量不要连着两夜不回家
Yeah, I just try not to be gone two nights in a row.
说到这个  如果你需要我再留一晚的话
Speaking of which, if, um, you need me to stay another night,
我能不能带个朋友过来
how would you feel about me having a friend over?
罗杰·奔跑·树吗
Roger Running Tree?
我...  我也是个有需求的女人
Well, I'm--I'm a woman with needs.
只要他不偷我们的食物  不在沙发上撒尿就行
As long as he doesn't steal our food or piss on our sofa.
菲奥娜  他是个基督徒
Fiona, he's a Christian.
-杰夫瑞·达莫[连环杀人犯]也是  -真的吗
- So was Jeffrey Dahmer. - Really?
我会在睡觉之前回来的  有事打给我
I'll be back before bedtime. Call if you need anything.
好的  好好玩
Okay, okay. Have fun.
所以我们就用他的手机拍了点小视频
So we'd make these little videos on his phone, right?
就为了自娱自乐什么的
Thought it was just for our own personal use or whatever.
然后有一天  我在大卖场
Then one day, I'm at the stop and shop,
翻包找优惠券的时候
digging around for my stamps,
有个变态一直盯着我
This craggy fella keeps looking at me
好像他认识我一样
like he knows me.
但我从来没见过他
Never seen him before.
他说  你看起来好眼熟
Goes, "you're so familiar."
-糟了  -最后
- No. - Finally...
晴天霹雳
Lightning bolt.
色情网站
YouPorn.
"我的发骚贱货老婆喜欢我干她腋窝"
"My skank, slutty wife loves to get armpit fucked."
不是吧
No.
你能相信这破事吗
Can you believe that shit?
我甚至都不介意"发骚贱货"几个字
I didn't even mind the "skank, slutty" part.
我气的是他说我喜欢腋窝被干
I was just pissed he said I liked taking it in the armpit.
谁会喜欢那个
Who likes that?
就是
No one.
我只是帮他个忙
Mm-hmm. I did it as a favor.
反正  他第二天早上就滚出去了
Anyway, he was out on his ass the next morning.
我下午就递交了离婚申请
I filed for divorce that afternoon.
公务员说  又来了吗
Clerk was like, "back again?"
这是第三位丈夫吗
This is husband number three?
是啊  第三次也没撞上好运气
Yep. Third time was not a charm.
对吧  恰奇
Right, Chuckie?
你这人似乎很乐观  体贴
You seem pretty upbeat, considering.
是啊  我宁愿屡屡遭遇挫折地活着  也不要...
Yeah. I guess I'd rather live and learn than just--
当个活死人
Not live at all.
没错
Yes.
就是啊
Exactly.
-你过得不容易吧  -是吧
- You've had a rough time of it. - Yeah, I guess.
我很惊讶竟然还没把你吓跑
Surprised I haven't scared you off yet.
我可没那么容易被吓着
I don't scare that easily.
你都没怎么吃你的薯条
You have barely touched your fries.
确定不要我再帮你叫杯啤酒吗
Are you sure I can't buy you another beer?
其实我是不喝酒的
I don't really drink.
你可能是第一个对我说这种话的男人
You might be the first man that's ever said that to me.
这是奶油糖果
This is--this is butterscotch.
我们点的是巧克力  我不能吃奶油糖果
We asked for chocolate. I can't eat butterscotch.
-你对它西过敏吗  -不  纯粹讨厌而已
- You allergic? - No, just hate it.
我也是
Me too.
那个和鳄梨
That and avocados.
鳄梨最恶心了
Avocados are the worst...
松鼠也是
And squirrels.
树上的大老鼠
Tree rats.
-太可恨了  -太可恨了
- Hideous. - Hideous.
宝贝
Baby,
去玩会儿弹珠吧  好吗
Go play some pinball. Okay?
他有自闭症吗
Is he autistic?
没有  他只是比较安静
Nah, he's just quiet--
有着深沉古老的灵魂
Very deep, old soul.
那个
So...
跟我介绍一下你自己吧
Tell me about you.
其实没什么可说的
Well, not really much to tell.
我是个简单的男人
I'm kind of a simple guy.
有孩子吗
Have kids?
有很多  至少50个
Uh, many... at least 50.
我把他们像杯垫一样堆叠在抽屉里
I stack 'em like coasters in a drawer.
你怎么这么幽默
Why are you so funny?
我喝高了
I'm high as a kite.
笑得真是开心
Ah, what a great laugh.
明天下午你有空吗
Are you free tomorrow afternoon?
应该有吧  怎么了
Should be. Why?
恰奇有场躲避球比赛
Chuckie's got a dodgeball game.
我希望有人陪我一起去看
I'd love some company in the stands.
虽然看上去像是南茜干了所有的活
And I know it looks like Nancy did all the work,
但清洗这些生菜  可是很耗体力的
But washing all this lettuce-serious labor.
女人都该知道怎么弄黄瓜哦
Your lady sure knows her way around a cucumber.
太重口了  妈
Whoa! Mom.
下次选别的蔬菜吧
Maybe choose another vegetable next time.
简  你能来说祷告词吗
Okay, Jane, would you say grace?
好的
Oh, sure.
兄弟们
Boys.
上帝  请保佑我们
Bless us, o lord,
我们即将蒙您恩赐  收获许多礼物
and these gifts which we are about to receive from thy bounty,
以基督之名
In christ's name.
-阿门  -阿门
- Amen. - Amen.
好了
All right.
好了  开吃吧
All right, dig in.
瞧瞧你们这些混蛋
Look at all you bougie bastards.
你怎么会来这儿
What are you doing here?
罗比
Robbie.
你看上去好极了
You look great.
你迟到了
You are late.
我得维护我的名声
Hey, I got to keep up my reputation.
罗比  你什么时候回来的
Hey, Robbie, when did you get back?
-今天下午  -好吧
- This afternoon. - Okay.
我完全不知道呢
I have no idea.
嘿  这是菲奥娜
Hey, this is Fiona.
菲奥娜  这位是我大哥  罗比
Fiona, I'd love you to meet my older brother, Robbie.
他一直在明尼苏达州的荒野中游荡
He's been off in the wilds of Minnesota with--what?
和一些驴友一起露营
Some buddies-you're camping for,
大概有几个月了吧
like, a few months, right?
你可以实话实说  麦克
You can be honest, Mike.
我没什么好隐瞒
Got nothing to hide.
我是又进了戒毒所接受巩固治疗
I was at a renewal retreat at my old rehab center.
到本周一  我已经戒毒三周年了
Three years sober this Monday...
中间有几次反复
With a couple detours.
-恭喜了  -干杯
- Congrats. - Yeah, cheers.
谢谢
Thank you.
感觉怎么样
So how was it?
那里有种超现实的感觉
Oh, it's unreal out there--
新鲜的空气  满天的繁星
the air, the stars.
我们开着雪地车狂奔
And we went snowmobiling.
各位  我被甩出车外几次
Guys, I took a couple wicked spills
身上可是留下了一些纪念品呢
and brought you back a souvenir.
别在餐桌上秀出来啊
Oh! Not at the table.
你看上去精神焕发
Well, you look great.
我感觉棒极了
I feel great.
-那真是太棒了  罗比  -是啊
- That's really great, Robbie. - Yeah.
-那简直好极了  -谢谢
- That's excellent. - Thank you.
我打算这周末
so I was thinking about going up
去湖边小屋一趟
to the lake house this weekend.
我和皮特打算去录音
Me and Pete need to lay down some tracks
需要个安静的环境
and need some peace to do it.
那边没人  对吧
No one's up there, are they?
罗比  我们谈过这事了
Robbie, we talked about this.
我们不希望你在没有
Um, we don't want you up there
家人陪伴的情况下下去那里
without someone else from the family.
好吧  我以为那是过去的事了呢
Yeah, I thought that was the past.
不  只是现在可能还为时过早
No, it's just-it might be too soon.
难道你怕我偷走你的长筒靴吗
Well, what am I gonna steal-your old waders?
那边没什么东西能卖的  对吧
There's nothing up there to sell, right?
等等  那里有台用了十年了电视机
Oh, wait. There's that ten-year-old tv.
兄弟  过些时候再说吧
Hey, man, you know, just give yourself a couple of weeks.
可以先安顿下来  了解一下各种状况
Like, maybe settle in, see how things go, and...
-谁问你了  麦克  -好了  别闹了
- Who asked you, Mike? - Hey, hey, knock it off.
你这样可不讲理
It's not unreasonable.
我忘了这里的人都有多讲理
Oh, I forgot how reasonable everyone around here is.
我的错
My bad.
没人想故意伤你的心  亲爱的
Oh, no one is out to hurt you, sweetheart.
也没人帮我
No one's out to help me either.
是啊  老爸付了两万块的戒毒费
Oh, yeah. Dad footing the $20,000 rehab bill
-还不算帮你吗  -滚一边去  麦克
- wasn't help enough. - Fuck off, Mike.
-嘿  别这样   -冷静
- Hey, hey, come on. - Hey, easy.
罗比  这里的每个人都想帮你
Robbie, everyone here has done nothing but try to help you,
-所以  -我会把钱还给他的
- So... - I'm gonna pay him back.
你别为这事操心  好吗
So don't you worry about it, okay?
我不是这个意思  罗比  你知道的
Well, that's not the point, Robbie, and you know it.
好了  算了
Okay. All right.
-罗比  坐下  -你要走了吗
- Robbie, sit. - You gonna go?
亲爱的
Oh, honey.
妈  谢谢你做的晚餐
Mom, thank you for dinner.
亲爱的  我真希望你能留下来
Oh, honey, I wish you would stay.
奥斯卡和内特  下次再收拾你们
Oscar and Nate, catch you punks later.
很高兴见到你  菲奥娜
Nice meeting you, Fiona.
真棒
Nice.
你这话当真吗
Are you serious?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我哥  他自己有些麻烦需要解决
My brother-he's got some issues to work out.
家庭乱状对我来说是家常便饭
Family chaos is my status quo.
-把土豆传过来吧  -小心点  很重的
- Pass the potatoes? - Careful, it's heavy.
现在撒尿也得付钱了吗
Now we got to pay to take a leak?
你可以去后面巷子里撒
There's always the alley,
只要你不介意把蛋蛋冻掉
If you don't mind freezing your nuts off.
酒都涨价了
We're already dishing out more for booze.
-撒尿还要钱啊  -才四分钱
- Our piss should be free. - It's a quarter.
算是补偿你们以前没给的小费
Consider it payback for the tips you don't leave.
这酒吧到底是有多缺钱
How hard up is this place, anyway?
厕纸没收费你们就该偷笑了
Hey, you're lucky I don't charge you people for toilet paper.
你们太浪费了了
You use too much.
只要三张就够了啊
All you need is three sheets--
一张往上擦  一张往下擦  一张打个光
One up, one down, one to polish.
你打什么光
What are you polishing?
算了不要回答  看着酒吧  我去吐一下
Never mind, watch the bar. I got to go puke.
亲爱的  这次记得瞄准下水道
Can you please aim for the drain this time?
她为什么不用付钱
Why doesn't she have to pay?
员工福利  免费呕吐
Employees puke for free.
我喜欢红头发的人
I like fucking carrot-tops,
最好有点雀斑
like, with the freckles
白皮肤  长得跟外星人一样
and the pale skin and fucking alien-looking.
那你走运了
Well, you might be in luck.
先请她喝一杯吧
Why don't you buy her a beverage?
不需要
I don't need to.
要不要来一发
Hey, you want to bang?
-我像不想的样子吗  -都听好
- Do I look busy? - Listen up!
这里有氧可酮  维柯丁  镇痛剂  阿普唑仑  兴奋剂
I got oxy, vicodin, percocet, xanax, adderall,
吗啡  安定剂
morphine, and valium--
五美元一粒  多买有折扣
5 bucks a pill, less if you buy in bulk.
价钱有点贵吧
Seems kind of steep, don't it?
我需要钱来买医院用的吸奶器
Not if I want to buy myself a hospital-grade pump.
得用强力一点的
I need something with strong suction.
这对儿玩意得喂饱四个
These puppies got to feed four.
四个
Four?
卡萝不能自己喂吗
What, Carol can't feed her own?
你是说我们让她打掉的那个吗
You mean the one we asked her to abort?
等她理我了我再告诉你
I'll let you know when she starts speaking to me again.
我要四片阿普唑仑和一片安定
Give me four xanies and a valium,
再来杯水
Glass of water, huh?
26块
26 bucks.
5块一片是25啊
5 pills at $5 is $25.
水还要1块
Water's a buck.
要高潮了  快点
Oh, I'm gonna come. Yeah, yeah!
真不错
Done.
舒服  你要继续吗
Whoo! You want to finish?
换位置
Switch positions.
什么
What?
快点
Just do it.
抓住我的屁股干我
Grab my hips. Pound my ass.
用什么干
With what?
靠  使劲儿撞就是了
Your fucking hip bones. Jesus.
怎么样  喜欢吗
Yeah, huh? You like it like that?
这样你很爽吗  是不是很舒服
Yeah? You like it like that? Huh? Huh? Oh, yeah.
晚上好  崽子们
Evening, spawn.
搅拌机在哪里
Where's the blender?
就在  就在这里  弗兰克
It's right-- it's right here, Frank.
你...
Oh.
天哪
Oh, god.
天哪  不要
Oh, god, no.
别这样  弗兰克
Don't do that, frank.
不要啊  不要这样
No, no. No, don't do it.
我的天哪
Oh, Jesus.
老有男人给我发穿内裤的照片
And I keep getting pictures of men
而且还鼓鼓的
in their underpants with bulges.
我根本不知道DTF什么意思
I-I have no idea what D.T.F. meant.
霍莉总这么说  我也不知道什么意思
Holly says it a lot. I'm not sure what it stands for.
你好啊
Hey, kid.
在高等学府读书[嗑药]感觉如何
How's higher learning?
我没嗑药  不过我在学习
Well, I'm not high, but I might be learning.
-看来你进步了  -利普好
- Sounds like progress. - Hi, Lip.
黛比跟你打招呼呢
Debbie says hi. She's
-她在写作业  -是吗  什么课
- She's doing homework. - Oh, yeah? What class?
李斯特老师的化学课
Uh, chemistry-- Mr. Lister.
我操  老带着氧气罐那家伙吗
Holy shit. The guy with the oxygen tank?
-他还活着呢  -差不多
- He's still alive? - Barely.
卡尔很愿意跟你打招呼  不过他在喂狗喝酒
And Carl would say hi, but he's getting his dog drunk.
卡尔养狗了
Wait, Carl has a dog?
是啊  他捡了一条流浪狗回家
Yeah, just some stray he brought home.
对了  你们平时用笔记本电脑吗
Um, hey, listen, are you guys using the laptop?
我上课需要用
I kind of need it for class.
黛比用来写作业
Well, Debbie uses it for school,
卡尔用来看黄片
and Carl uses it for porn.
你那里能借到吗
Uh, can you borrow one from over there?
当然  能借到  没事
Yeah. Yeah, sure. No--no problem.
你还好吗
Hey, you okay?
我
Uh...
不怎么样  就是...
I could be better. You know, it's--
我有点...
I'm--I'm a little-- it's--
不适应吗
Different?
对  不适应
Different, yeah.
你也是吗
Yeah, you too?
那当然
God, yes. Come on.
每天早上都得穿紧身窄裙
I put on pencil skirts every morning,
看着镜子总感觉"你谁啊"
and I'm like, "Who are you?"
看来你也进步了
Sounds like progress.
是啊  加拉格一家在向上爬
Yeah, the Gallaghers moving up the food chain.
是啊  慢慢地往上爬
Yeah, one rusty link at a time.
你错过派对了
Aw, you're missing your party.
没事  没什么的
Oh, no, no, no. It's--it's okay.
不行  去玩吧
No, no. Go have fun.
我们很想你
We miss you.
We miss you!
没...
Well, o--
-快点  -抱歉
- Come on. - I'm sorry.
我要掉下床了
I'm falling off the bed right now.
今晚我邀请我哥跟我们一起吃晚餐
So I invited my brother out to dinner with us tonight.
昨晚的事我觉得很内疚  所以
I feel so bad about what happened last night, so...
看来你们之间有点问题需要解决
Well, seems like you guys have some stuff you need to work out.
他总是能戳到我的火点  你懂吗
He just pushes my buttons, you know?
我得换一种解决方式
I got to find a different way to react.
是啊
Right.
不如再叫你爸爸花两万块
Why not have your dad throw another 20 grand
但愿这样能解决问题
at his problems and hope they go away?
我家房子都不值那么多钱
Dude, my house isn't even worth that much.
那我能怎么办
Okay, well, what's the alternative--
不理他吗
I just slam the door on him?
可以啊
Why not?
他是我的家人
He's family.
以前有一次
You know, this one time,
我被人揍得很惨
I was getting the crap kicked out of me, okay?
罗比看到了  冲过来
Robbie sees it, storms over,
一把抓住那俩孩子的头发
he grabs both these kids by the hair,
把他们扔进雪堆里
hurls them into a snowbank...
狠狠揍了一顿
knocks 'em senseless.
-天哪  -是吧
- Jesus. - I know.
他保护了我很多年  你懂吗
Yeah, he was my protector for years, you know?
现在该我来保护他了
I don't mind being his for a while.
是这样
Hey, um, listen,
今天我得早点走
I need to take off a little early today.
昨晚通宵写哲学论文来着
I was up all night working on my philosophy paper,
而且文学考试完全没准备
and I didn't get to crack one book for my lit exam.
不行
Denied.
听着  我拿着奖学金
Look, I didn't get a scholarship
可不是为了在这里给其他学生做饭吃
so that I could shovel hash browns into the mouths of entitled undergrads.
好吗
All right?
我是认真的  我得学习
No, no, no. Seriously, I need to study.
我很同情你  真的
No, man, I feel for you. I really do.
我知道半工半读有多艰难
I know how hard it is juggling classes and work.
我一直看到其他孩子苦作挣扎
I see other kids struggling with it all the time,
但他们都做到了
but they get there.
怎么做到的
Yeah, how?
几个字
Three words--
合理分配时间
Time-management skills.
计划好是最重要的
It's about planning.
我过去总是忙得焦头烂额
I used to be all over the place,
-就跟你一样  菲尔  -是利普
- just like you, Phil. - Lip.
然后我上了个有关提高效率的网络讲座
And then I took a webinar on increasing productivity,
彻底改变了我的生活
and it changed my life.
我不需要什么网络讲座
Okay, see, I don't need a webinar.
我只要半小时时间复习文学
I need an extra 30 minutes to study for lit.
很抱歉  办不到
I'm sorry, man. I can't help you.
你可以的  宝贝
You got this, baby.
你可以的
You got this.
把鼻子按住  宝贝儿
Bear down, baby. Bear down.
这个裁判太水了
This ref is a nightmare.
他要是多长只眼  那就是独眼巨人了
If he had another eye, he'd be a Cyclops.
我以为躲避球没裁判的呢
I thought dodgeball didn't even have refs.
需要裁判的  有很多比分
They need 'em-multiple outs.
大孩子联手对付弱势的小朋友
The big kids gang up on the weaker ones.
裁判  你错过一场精彩球赛了
Yo, ref, you're missing a great game out there.
是啊  你的导盲犬呢
Yeah, where's your seeing eye dog?
忍痛呼吸  恰奇
Breathe through the pain, Chuckie.
泪往肚里吞
Cry on the inside.
你没事的  宝贝
You're okay, baby.
天哪  那孩子可真经打
Boy, that kid can take a beating.
跟两块钱的牛排一样坚硬
Tough as a $2 steak.
不知怎的  弗兰克  我觉得像是
I don't know why, Frank, but I feel like
认识你很久了
I've known you my entire life.
我第一任丈夫是个瘾君子
Um, my first husband was an addict.
如果你嗑药的话
So, if you're into substance abuse,
现在就告诉我  我不能再经历这种事了
tell me right now, 'cause I can't go through that again.
完全合法
Completely legal,
有医嘱的止痛药
doctor-sanctioned pain management.
-你身上痛  -抽了就不痛了
- You're in pain? - Not when I'm baked.
哪儿痛
What hurts?
我的肝不好
I have this liver condition.
有多糟
How bad?
基本废了
Pretty much kicked.
医生说我需要一个新的
They say I need a new one.
你是说肝脏移植
You mean a-a transplant?
那些高学历的家伙是这么跟我说的
That's what the folks with the fancy degrees keep telling me.
弗兰克
Oh, Frank...
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
还来
More?
你能带它们上楼吗
Do you mind taking them upstairs?
罗杰·奔跑·树随时会来
Because Roger Running Tree is coming here any second.
他好像对动物尿液和学步小孩过敏
I think he's sensitive to animal urine and--and toddler.
把它们放你床上
Put 'em on your beds and stuff.
-又带狗回来  -第一条没人认领
- More dogs? - Nobody claimed the first one.
也许这些狗就是被人遗弃的
Maybe they were trying to get rid of them.
天哪  你要上哪去
Jesus. Where--where are you going?
霍莉要办过夜派对
Holly's having a sleepover party.
是吗  菲奥娜没跟我说啊
Really? Because Fiona didn't tell me about that.
-她肯定是忘了  -好吧
- She must've forgot. - Oh, okay.
好好玩
Well, have so much fun.
等一下
Um, just a--just a second.
等一下  马上来
Just one second. Just a second.
来了
Coming.
你一定是罗杰了  请进
You must be Roger. Come in.
希拉
Sheila.
你本人更性感
You're even foxier in person.
嘴真甜
Oh, that's so sweet.
天哪  好漂亮
They're-gosh, they're beautiful.
你要把外套脱了
would you--would you like to take your coat off
来杯美妙的冰气泡酒吗
and have a nice glass of chilled sparkling wine?
我把吉他放车上了
I left my guitar in the Honda.
我不知道你对弹唱有没有兴趣
I wasn't sure if you'd be interested in a little strum-down.
我可以跑回车上去拿
I can just run right back out and fetch it.
好啊
Yes. Yes, I would.
我对弹唱非常感兴趣
I would be very interested in a strum-down.
-我马上回来  -好
- I'll be right back. - Okay.
小麦  这儿有单一麦芽威士忌
Oh, Mikey, they have single-malt flights.
格兰昆奇  莱根法尔林
Glenkinchie, Lagavulin...
不不  今晚不喝
No. No, no, no, not tonight.
喝吧  让我通过你间接感受下
Come on, get it, so I can drink vicariously through you.
不用了
No, man.
说真的  我真的无所谓今晚不喝酒
Seriously, I'm totally fine not drinking tonight.
-需要什么饮品吗  -来杯苏格兰威士忌
- Can I start you of some drinks? - Yeah, he'll take a scotch flight.
我操
God damn it.
再来一瓶
Uh, and a bottle of--
菲奥娜  你要红酒白酒
Fiona, you like red or white?
我无所谓
I'm not picky.
好吧  那就来瓶08年的乔丹吧
Okay, let's-let's do the 2008 Jordan.
我一个人可喝不完
Well, I can't really drink a whole bottle by myself.
没事  麦克会帮忙的
No. Mike will lend a hand.
我弟怎么会错过这种好酒呢
Little bro-ski can't pass up a silky cab, can he?
你俩怎么好上的
So how'd you guys start getting it on?
他邀请我去露营
Uh, well, he invited me camping...
明知我有男友
knowing I had a boyfriend.
我被她迷得神魂颠倒的
She makes me do crazy things.
于是我去了
So I went.
然后我灌醉了他
And then I got him drunk
差点在帐篷里上了他
and almost fucked him in a tent.
-什么  -真事
- What? - Yeah, true story.
她扑倒了我
She jumped me.
又不是什么自豪的事
Well, I'm not proud.
你这样对你老板
Well, you did this to your boss.
我有时是有一点狂野
I can get a little wild.
一点吗
A little?
我最近已经收敛多了
I've calmed down... Recently.
我怎么不太信呢
Somehow, I find that hard to believe.
谢谢
Thank you.
鲑鱼看起来挺美味的
The salmon looks yummy.
一  二  三
One, two, three...
天哪
Oh, God!
你今晚很棒  孩子  我为你骄傲
You did real good tonight, kiddo--I'm proud of you.
被这样打了还没吐
It takes a tough little bastard to take a beating
可真不简单
and not puke his guts out.
我吐了
I did puke.
事实上  他在第三节吐了
Actually, he did, third period.
这也没什么丢人的
Well, there's no shame in that, my friends.
我们到了
This is us.
谢谢你们给我带来的精彩夜晚
Well, thank you for an excellent evening.
要进来喝一杯吗
Would you like to come in for a nightcap?
管他呢
Ah, what the heck?
谢了
Thanks.
-你明白吗  -得时刻保持警觉
- You got it? - Got to get my wits about me.
不许看电视  明早还要上学呢  快去睡觉
Hey, no TV. School tomorrow-- bedtime.
不要
No!
-快去  -睡吧  小胖胖
- Oh, come on. Go, go, go. - Oh, come on, bruiser.
你的睡衣呢
Where are-where are your pjs?
我不喜欢睡衣
I don't like pjs.
-那你穿什么睡觉  -裸睡
- Well, what do you wear to bed? - Nothing.
你今晚就穿这个睡吧
Maybe tonight you could wear that.
快进去
In you go.
想喝点什么吗  水  可可
You need anything-- water, cocoa?
你口气臭得像狗屎
Your breath smells like dog poo.
晚安  恰奇
Night, Chuckles.
蔓越莓汁
Cranberry juice.
应该对肝脏有好处
Supposed to be, uh, good for the liver.
谢谢
Thanks.
你对他真好
You are so good with him.
是个好孩子
He's a good one.
弗兰克  你什么血型
Frank, what's your blood type?
O型  怎么了
"O" positive. Why?
我也是
That's my blood type.
是吗
Really?
太巧了
What a coincidence.
我想
I want...
把肝脏给你
to give you my liver.
什么  不行
What? No.
只是一小块  又不是全部
It's just a lobe, right? It's not the whole thing.
缺了它我又不会死掉
I'm not gonna, like, die without it or anything.
可是我们才刚认识
But we--we barely know each other.
我对你已经了解不少了
I know enough to know you...
你很善良
have a beautiful heart.
可是...
That's just...
你能活下去
Hey, look, you get to live.
我还会剩下不少肝脏呢
I'll still have plenty of liver left over.
这有什么不好呢
What's the downside?
手术可不是过家家
Well, the surgery's no walk in the park.
我身上可不止挨过两三刀
Oh, I have been sliced into more times than a side of beef.
你看
Here...
阑尾手术  剖腹产
Appendectomy, C-section,
疝气  脾脏手术  事故手术
hernia, spleen, accidental surgery,
二次修复手术
second surgery to fix that one.
-你看  这里  -好了  好了
- Look. I mean, look. - Okay, yeah, yeah.
好了  把衣服放下来
All right, I get-- put it down.
还是位绅士呢
And a gentleman too?
弗兰克  我被你迷住了
Frank, I think I'm smitten.
不不  哎呀  不要
Oh, no, jeez, no.
不要这样  听着
No--this--okay, listen...
你也喜欢我的
Shh. You feel it too.
-好吧  -我知道的
- Okay, gen-- - I know it.
说实话  我不太想进展太快
Generally speaking, I don't like to move this fast.
-我也是  -好的
- Me neither. - Okay.
但不知道我现在发了什么疯
I don't know what's got into me.
停下  别这样  不要
Stop. No. Okay. No, no. Okay.
对不起
Sorry.
-疼  -你没事吧
- Pain. - You okay?
失陪一下
Excuse me.
友谊日渐坚定
What started as a friendship
-感情因而萌发  -他在唱什么
- has grown stronger - What is he singing?
但愿我有勇气使它流逝
I only wish I had the strength to let it flow
快速马车的《无法控制这种感觉》
I Can't Fight This Feeling, by Reo Speedwagon.
谁让你告诉她我唱的啥  就你知道啊
You tell her what I'm doing. You know what I'm doing.
当他真心的时候就爱插科打诨唱这种歌
It's sort of his go-to song when he's feeling earnest.
-我还能唱很多歌  -你是真心的吗
- I sing more songs. - Aw. Are you feeling earnest?
你这次是真心的吗
Are you having an earnest moment?
为我人生导向
Give my life direction.
让一切如此清晰
You make everything so clear.
喝了这么多酒
Wine and scotch--
他真的醉得不行了
That's gonna be a hell of a hangover.
-你觉得愧疚吗  -才不
- Are you feeling guilty? - Nah.
看到他能放下包袱很好
It's great to see him cut loose like that.
-他简直是个工作狂  -是啊  没错
- He works his ass off. - Yeah, he does.
而且他干得很好
And he's good at it.
听着老套  不过我真为他骄傲
It's corny, but I'm proud of him.
他在公司里发一周的脾气
He kicks up a fury all week at the family firm,
然后周五下午回到家
then settles down Friday afternoon
喝点美味的啤酒  看会儿无聊的电视
to a delicious foamy beer and some lame tv.
他就心满意足了
And that's enough for him.
这样谁都会心满意足
Should be enough for anybody.
我不行  以前试过
Not me. Tried it once.
在公司里上过一个夏天的班
Worked for the CUPS one summer.
每天进出办公室
Showed up to that office
西装革履  好不风光
every day with my button-down and my shiny shoes.
但我差点疯掉
Nearly lost my mind.
为什么
Why?
生活给予我们挑战
Well, life throws challenges at us
从而看出我们是哪种人  对吧
to see what we're made of, right?
但是显然  我是一个嗜酒如命的人
Yeah, apparently, I'm made of Bourbon and Blow.
这样的工作无法让我安分太久
Yeah. A necktie can't hold that in very long.
但是你现在戒了
But you're clean now.
当然  暂时是戒了
Sure. Till I'm not.
我是嗜酒如命的酒鬼
I'm the worst kind of addict.
我喜欢快节奏的生活
I'm addicted to the rush of life.
充满酒精和毒品的生活
Which is primarily booze and drugs?
顺利的时候
When it's good,
你开怀大笑
man, you're laughing a lot,
你到处乱搞
you're screwing a lot.
世界如同被希望的曙光照耀
The world, like, glimmers with promise.
当倒霉的时候  无处可逃
And when it's bad, there is no getting out.
你以为孤单会让你停下
And you think that feeling alone would make you stop,
但是永远不会
but it never does.
但是你伤害别人  这不是更糟吗
But knowing you're hurting people, isn't that worse?
应该是
It should be...
但并没有
But, no, it isn't.
菲奥娜  我们都是瘾君子  想要填补空虚
We're all addicts, Fiona, just trying to fill a void.
只是有些人善于隐藏  是吧
Some of us are just better at hiding it, right?
啥
What?
他醒了
He's back.
让我们把船驶向海岸
Let's bring this ship back into shore
然后永远丢掉船桨
and throw away the oars forever.
我真的很喜欢做菜
You know, I really love making dinner.
以后我要好好学学怎么做
Someday I'm gonna learn how to really do it,
必要的话上个烹饪学校
like, go to culinary school even.
吃龙虾你想配什么饮料
Oh, what'd you want to drink with your scampi?
随便
Uh, whatever you're having.
那就激浪汽水了
Mountain Dew it is.
《橡皮头》可能是我最爱看的电影了
You know, Eraserhead might be my favorite movie of all time.
所营造的那种氛围
It's like this atmospheric,
恐怖的梦境...
horrific dreamscape--
我这样会勾起你的性致吗
Does this make you cray?
黛比
Um--uh, Debbie?
我哪里做错了吗
Am I doing it wrong?
不  不不不
No. No, no, no.
只是  我们不必这样
It's not--it's just, like, we don't have to do this.
没关系的  今晚我不用回家
It's okay. I don't have to go home tonight.
我给家人说在别人家过夜
I told them I'd be at a sleepover.
不  不是这个  是我的原因
No, it's not--no, no, no. I'm--I'm--it's me.
我不...  原因很复杂
I'm not--it's a lot of things.
我只是现在感觉工作上特别累
I'm just really stressed out at work right now,
我妈还来电话了
and my mom called.
她说家里的猫病了  所以...
She said that the family cat's sick, so...
不是吧
Oh, no.
是啊  时机不好  仅此而已
Yeah, it's just-- it's awkward timing, is all.
好吧
Okay.
不过你真漂亮
But you look beautiful, though.
谢谢
Thank you.
龙虾看起来很好吃
Scampi looks delicious.
谢谢
Thanks.
来
Uh, here...
披上这个
Here, let's do this.
好了
There.
好的  准备好了吗
Okay. You ready?
做好吓尿的准备吧
Prepare your mind to be blown.
保佑动物们和孩子们
Bless the beasts and the children.
因为这个世界并非他们所看到的那样
For the world can never be the world they see.
罗杰  这是卡尔
Roger, this is Carl.
他住这里
He lives here.
很高兴见到你
Pleased to meet you.
你知道《对魔鬼的同情》这首歌吗
Do you know "Sympathy For the Devil"?
我试过给你搞药了
I tried to get your drugs,
但小维给药柜上了锁
but V has her cabinet locked up,
她现在要收钱才肯给我
and she's making me buy them now.
我绑架了这些狗  等人来赎它们
I kidnapped these dogs, holding them for ransom.
但是没用
It's not working.
你别担心了
Don't--don't sweat it.
我也许找到新肝了
I may have found a liver.
真的吗  哪里找到的
Really? Where?
你的大姐  萨咪
Your older sister Sammi.
她真有性格
She's really something.
晚安
Good night.
好了  好了
All right. Okay.
-起来  就快到了  兄弟  -好嘞
- Here we go. Almost there, brother. - Oh! Okay.
马上到了
Almost there.
-来吧  -到了
- Come on. - There you go.
好了好了
Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
到了  吐吧
There you are. Here you go.
-好了  -尽情吐吧
- All right. - Okay, there you are.
加油
Okay. Oh, hey!
-你做到了  -不
- You made it. - Oh, no.
-吐吧  -不
- There you go. - Oh, no.
老天
Oh, god.
-水在这里  -好的
- There's water. - Okay.
就在你右手旁边
Right by your right hand.
-好的  -好吗
- Okay. - Okay?
-好  -好
- Okay. - Okay.
我从没见过他这幅模样
I've never seen him like that.
他很少喝这么多
He rarely drinks that much.
上次是伊芙离开他的时候
Last time was when Eve left him.
-他的前任  -妻子  对
- His ex. - Wife, yeah.
关于她的事我知道的不多
I haven't heard much about her.
她差点弄死他了
Well, she nearly killed him.
他还以为是自己的错  但并不是
He thought it was his fault. It wasn't.
你觉得他睡过去了吗
You think he passed out?
希望是吧
One would hope.
那你呢
And what about you?
我怎么了
What about me?
你是打算长久跟他交往下去
Are you the sticking-around type
还是随便玩玩的
or the screwing-around type?
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
我们只在一起几个月
We've only been going out a couple months.
别怪我保护意识太强
Well, you can't blame me for being protective.
他看起来非常喜欢你
He seems to really dig you.
我也一样
Well, feeling's mutual.
他可比我上一任男友好太多了
And he's, like, a "jazillion" times more sane
所以我很开心
than my last one, so I'm happy.
是吗
Are you?
好吧
Okay.
怎么了
What?
没事
Nothing.
-要喝咖啡吗  -好的  麻烦你了
- You want some coffee? - Yes, please.
我觉得葡萄酒有点上头
I think this wine went to my head a little.
不是什么好咖啡  希望你喝的惯
Oh, it's not shade-grown. Hope you can handle that.
是吧  通常我只喝有机的
Oh, yeah, well, I usually only drink organic,
-公平贸易认证过的  -是吗
- you know, Fair Trade. - Yeah.
还早呢
It's early.
老天  真抱歉
Jesus. Sorry about that.
-怎么了  -那个吻痕
- What? - The hickey.
昨晚不是故意对你那么粗鲁的
I didn't mean to get rough with you last night.
没关系  我都没发现
Oh. That's okay. I barely felt it.
我要先回家了
I'm--I'm gonna get home for a while
看看孩子们怎么样
and check on the kids.
等会儿你去公司吗
Will I see you at work later?
不确定  不知道  可能会请个病假吧
I'm not sure. I don't know. I might call in sick.
-要我送你回去吗  -不用
- Here, you want me to drive you? - No.
我不认为你能通过酒精检测
I don't think you'd pass a breathalyzer.
开我的车回去吧  好吗
Okay, well, take my car, okay?
不用  我乘轻轨就行
No, I just-- I'll just take the EL.
过一小时打给你
Call you in an hour?
看看你到时怎么样了
See how you're doing?
好的
Okay.
谢谢  宝贝  你是最好的
Thanks, baby. You're the best.
早  昨晚顺利吗
Morning. How'd it go last night?
希拉逼你听《扑通》了吗
Did Sheila force "Kerplunk" on you?
绿日乐队1992年发行的专辑
我知道  这周第二次在麦克家过夜了
I know, I know. Two nights this week at Mike's.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
近期我不会再去他家了
I won't be going over there again for a while.
我根本没注意到你不在
I didn't even know you were gone.
-你的脖子怎么了  -疹子
- What's wrong with your neck? - Weird rash.
是嘴巴形状的
It's mouth-shaped.
今天就要发之前的作业了
We got our papers back today.
这么快  你昨天才交上去的
That quick? You just turned it in yesterday.
是啊  那家伙就是台机器
Yeah, that guy's a machine.
谁知道他看了没有
Who knows if he even reads them?
我只是庆幸自己按时完成了
I'm just glad I finished it.
恭喜你  兄弟
Well, congrats, man.
还有  谢谢你
And, hey, thanks.
我真的很感谢你
You know, I really appreciate you
借我电脑用
letting me use your computer.
你救了我一命
You saved my ass.
老天  又是快闪活动
Chst, another flash mob.
你们这次的作业都很不错
You all did terrific on these.
周二的期中考试前
Please use them
请务必借助它们复习
to study for your midterm on Tuesday.
谢谢
Thank you.
有进步  你渐渐开始懂得怎么梳理自己的想法了
距离阐述合理的论据又近了一步  继续努力
早呀  美人
Morning, sunshine.
我要去上班了
Uh, I'm just about to head to the office.
该怎么跟其他同事说
What should I tell people?
跟他们说昨晚你在流理台上搞了我哥
Oh, that you fucked my brother last night on the counter
当时我正倒在厕所的呕吐物里
while I laid in a puddle of vomit.
麦克的电话为什么在你那
Why do you have Mike's phone?
电话在流理台上  看见你来电
It's on the counter. I saw you calling.
觉得必须跟你打个招呼
Felt compelled to say howdy.
不  你在那里干嘛
No. Why are you there?
别紧张
Relax.
我是来帮我爸拿清雪车的钥匙的
I just came over to get the snowblower keys for pop.
-他在那里吗  -谁  我爸吗
- Is he there? - Who--pop?
麦克
Mike.
睡得正香呢
Sleeping like a baby.
看来今天没人陪你吃午餐了
Looks like you're flying solo for lunch today.
我永远不会告诉他的  知道了吗
I'm not telling him, ever, okay?
我们要把这秘密带进坟墓
We're taking this to our graves
这事根本没发生过
This did not happen.
实实在在的发生了呢
Oh, yes, it did.
而且它会再次发生
And it's gonna happen again...
很快就会  上瘾了
Very soon, addict.
照顾你们竟然还让我赔钱了
You assholes actually cost me money.
自由了  狂奔吧
Be free. Run wild.
滚蛋
Go.